Finding Aid for Alpha Nu Literary Society (University of Michigan) Records, 1843-1931
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Alpha Nu Literary Society (University of Michigan) records 1843-1931
Alpha Nu Literary Society (University of Michigan)
3 linear ft.
8717 Bimu F41/2
University of Michigan student organization established in 1843 for the "intellectual improvement of its members." Members presented literary papers, held debates, and issued a manuscript periodical entitled "The Sybil." The record group consists of organizational records and “The Sybil.”
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group was transferred from the Library of the University of Michigan (donor 1278 ).
The record group is open to research.
The Alpha Nu Literary Society was formed in 1843 by students of the University of Michigan for the intellectual improvement of its members. The members of the organization debated literary topics, wrote essays which were then read to the group, and issued (in its earlier decades) a manuscript periodical entitled "The Sybil."
The record group consists of such organizational records as minutes of meetings, constitution and by-laws, treasurer's books, inventories of the Alpha Nu Library, membership book, and scattered correspondents and business papers. Correspondents in the papers include Lewis Cass, April 1846, Robert McClelland, January 1846, Henry R. Schoolcraft, December 1845,and Ezra C. Seaman. Also included are volumes of the manuscript periodical, "The Sybil," which date (with several gaps), from 1843 to 1931. Most of "The Sybil" are from the early period of Alpha Nu, 1843 to 1854.
Subjects:
University of Michigan--Honorary societies.; University of Michigan--Students--Societies, etc.
Contributors:
Cass, Lewis, 1782-1866.; McClelland, Robert, 1807-1880.; Schoolcraft, Henry Rowe, 1793-1864.; Seaman, Ezra C. (Ezra Champion), 1805-1880.; The Sybil
- Organizational records
  - Correspondence, 1845-1850
    - 1845 (Box 1)
    - 1846-1850 (Box 1)
  - Papers, 1845-1860 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous business papers, 1868-1885 (Box 1)
  - Minutes, 1859-1923
    - 1859-1868 (Box 1)
    - 1868-1884 (Box 1)
    - 1884-1900 (Box 1)
    - 1900-1914 (Box 1)
    - 1914-1923 (Box 1)
  - Constitution and By-Laws, 1843 (Box 1)
  - Constitution and By-Laws, 1845 (Box 1)
  - Revised Constitution and By-Laws, 1867 (Box 1)
  - Revised Constitution and By-Laws, 1931 (Box 1)
  - Membership book, 1900-1929 (Box 2)
  - Treasurer's book, 1855-1862 (Box 2)
    - Treasurer's book, 1855-1862
    - Treasurer's book, 1862-1881 (Box 2)
    - Treasurer's book, 1885-1890 (Box 2)
  - Account books, 5 volumes (Box 2)
  - Catalogue of the Alpha Nu Library, 7 volumes (Box 2)
- Manuscript periodical
  - The Sibyl, 1844-1931
    - 1844-1845 (Box 3)
    - 1846-1850 (Box 3)
    - 1851 (Box 3)
    - 1852 (Box 3)
    - 1853 (Box 3)
    - 1854 (Box 3)
    - 1863 (Box 3)
    - March 5, 1910, October 22, 1910 and January 21, 1921 (Box 3)
    - 1931 (Box 3)